David Quintero

SUMMARY

Software engineer with 3 years of training as a Full-Stack and Front-End web developer. With a passion for building responsive, elegant and engaging experiences with future friendly web technologies such as React, Node.js, Express and MongoDB. I invite you to please take a moment to **explore my developer portfolio** and experience my skills for yourself at: https://davidquintero.dev

FEATURED PROJECTS

HomeWorks — Full-Stack Lead Generation/CRM App (React, Node.js, Express, MongoDB) – 200+ hours project

- This app allows a customer to request services at their home address. The app organizes the request by dates and keeps track of the flow from initial contact, estimate and service completion. It features a testimonial system, use of the Google Maps API (address autocomplete, map), real-time updates using Socket.IO, user registration: authentication & authorization, i18n language internationalization and a sleek and fully responsive mobile-first layout.
- This full-stack project combines every aspect of web development. It is also a fully deployed commercial application generating revenue for its company. This **featured project** can be accessed through https://homeworks.davidquintero.dev A four-step tour is available. Source available in my GitHub.
- App is deployed using Docker containers for the front-end and the back-end, a CI/CD workflow is in place using GitHub Actions and Watchtower.

Web Scraper/Twitter Bot (Node.js, MongoDB)

- This bot scrapes the latest posts from LessWrong.com (an online community dedicated to human rationality and AI development) and tweets the latest entries every hour. Technologies used were MongoDB and Node.js as well as the Twitter API.
- This bot allows anyone who wishes to keep up with the latest publications from this community to receive **hourly** updates if they turn on notifications for its Twitter handle at <u>@lesswrong_bot</u> source available in my GitHub.

CERTIFICATIONS

Full Stack Developer Certification | 1200 hours coursework

freeCodeCamp.org • 2019-2020

JavaScript Data Structures & Algorithms • Provided a comprehensive understanding of the JavaScript language, Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), as well as developing a problem-solving mental model. **Responsive Web Design** • Understanding semantic HTML5 and CSS3 as well as important UX/UI methodology. **Frontend Libraries** • Creating applications using React, managing states, abstraction and components. **APIs and Microservices** • In depth exploration of Node.js and the Express library to create and web servers, API end points and microservices.

TECHNOLOGIES

Front End: React | HTML5 | CSS3 | TailwindCSS | AdobeXD | Figma Back End: Node | Express | MongoDB | GraphQL | Postman DevOps: Linux | Docker | GitHub Actions | git | yarn | npm Testing: Jest | Selenium

WORK HISTORY

Web Developer

UpWork

March 2020 - Present, Remote

- Have developed and customized Shopify store themes using Liquid, JavaScript, HTML5 and CSS3.
- Linux server administration and DNS projects.
- WordPress blog set-up and development for academic professionals.

Store Manager

The UPS Store

February 2016 - March 2020, Orlando, FL

- I was a store manager and lead graphic designer. Had the privilege of supporting a small team provide exceptional service to the community promoting a culture of inclusivity and kindness.
- I worked on hundreds of marketing projects for all types of businesses and causes in the downtown Orlando area. We offered in-store industrial printing capability, booklets, postcards, posters, banners, foam-core mounting, etc. Highly creative and highly rewarding jobs. This position exposed me to hundreds of business ventures, marketing strategies, success stories, and good creative energy and collaboration with clients when designing their artwork and delivering finished products.

EDUCATION

A.A. General Studies (Enrolled)

Valencia College • Orlando, FL • 2022 • 3.0 GPA